The Lion and the Mouse.
A Lion asleep in his lair was waked up by
a Mouse running over his face.
Losing his temper he seized it with his
paw and was about to kill it. The Mouse,
terrified, piteously entreated him to
spare its life. "Please let me go,"
it cried, "and one day I will repay you
for your kindness." The idea of so
insignificant a creature ever being able
to do anything for him amused the Lion so
much that he laughed aloud,
and good-humouredly let it go.
But the Mouse's chance came, after all.
One day the Lion got entangled in a net
which had been spread for game by some
hunters, and the Mouse heard and
recognised his roars of anger and ran to
the spot. Without more ado it set to work
to gnaw the ropes with its teeth,
and succeeded before long in setting the
Lion free. "There!" said the Mouse,
"you laughed at me when I promised I would
repay you: but now you see,
even a Mouse can help a Lion."